Martin Brignall

August 29, 2024



email | github | 07766027602 112 Aubrey Road, Bristol, BS3 3EU

ABOUT ME

Over the past 5 years, I have honed my skills in the DevOps/DevSecOps space. I currently work as a Cyber Defence Engineer as escalated Incident Response. We deal with reports/alerts as broad as phishing/business email compromise to GuardDuty alerting or malware. I have a strong interest in the software development pipeline. I love learning, and use self development to increase my understanding.

EXPERIENCE

OVO Energy, Bristol - Cyber Defence Engineer

May 2024 to Present

- Building a bond between ticketing system of our MSSP and OVO (saving 30k)
- Working with leading technologies in SOC/Threat Detection/SIEM
 - Google Chronicle/Workspace/SecOps
 - Sublime Email Security
 - CrowdStrike
 - GuardDuty
 - Tines (Security Automation)
 - Wiz
- Escalated Incident Response (Blue Team)

OVO Energy, Bristol - Developer Tooling Specialist

August 2022 - May 2024

- Cloud services optimization (AWS, Google Cloud) for scalability, reliability, and targeted cost reduction
- Building automated vending for GCP projects as guardrails
- Drive DevOps and DevEx practices, streamlining development workflows, and facilitating seamless collaboration between development and operations teams

- Champion collaboration and knowledge sharing within the engineering community
- Vendor engagement and billing/cost reconciliation

OVO Energy, Bristol - Enterprise Technology Specialist

March 2021 - August 2022

- Jira Cloud Administration for all Atlassian products
- Introduced zero-touch deployment using Mosyle, a pioneering MDM tool for Apple devices
- Linux device management solution including device scripting

OVO Energy, Bristol - Tech Support Analyst

June 2019 - August 2022

- Provided technical support and automated Jira projects for enhanced productivity
- Service Desk Front Line Support
- Covid Office Cover

INTERESTS/SKILLS

- Home Lab | Proxmox | Containers (Docker)
- WebDev | Django | Python
- Terraform | Cloudflare
- NixOS | Linux | Emacs
- AWS | GCP | Postgres

For the last two years I've been managing a website that supports the Tobacco Factory Sunday Market. This was the perfect opportunity to hone my web development skills and I chose to use Django/Python, home served using Proxmox and served to the web with Cloudflare. From here I began to approach my own CI/CD and automated deployments to better understand how best to apply these practices.

TRAINING

- Webdev Bootcamp
- AWS Developer
- Jira fundamentals and Atlassian University
- Google Labs/ Security Foundations
- Immersive Labs
- ACE Community Leader